What's up, Dolph fans? We are continuing
our series here with Dolphin Scouts and
Decision Makers, the folks that build
the team here. I'm joined today by Brock
Ron Brockington, senior national scout
for your Miami Dolphins. Thanks for your
time today, man. We appreciate it.
>> Thanks for having me. I appreciate it.
>> Yeah, we're excited to talk to you
because a long journey across the NFL
that brings you here to Miami, 20 years
with the Dolphins, three decades across
the NFL. We've been starting these off
by just talking to you guys about your
journey, man. Your path here. It's it's
a long road to get to these spots in
this league, and you've well earned it.
I just kind of want to hear you talk a
little bit about your your journey to
the NFL and and where you are here
today.
>> Yeah, you know, I grew up in New York
and um once I was done playing ball, I
just I was still competitive. I wanted
to find a different avenue that I still
can be involved in and um you know, the
NFL some aspect. You know, coaching was
really not my thing. So, uh the next
avenue was scouting and it's kind of how
I got started. Uh I started my career at
the Jets. Um Dick Haley was one of my
mentors. um he really kind of got me
involved in the business and what to
look for and worked in a parcel. So um
just a good group of of higherups to
kind of show me and lead me the way of
you know personnel evaluation. Um so
that's kind of the path and then you
know realistically I looked at it you
know I had a proday and the numbers
weren't weren't as good so kind of led
to like obviously more like personnel
stuff. So then uh kind of the rest is
history. But you know you know that's a
three decades is is pretty long. You
know just consistency, discipline, just
work ethic and just kind of staying in
my lane has kind of been the the best
avenue for me to be where I'm at right
now.
>> I love talking to former players that
turn scouts because it does seem like
coaching seems to be more of the avenue
those guys funnel towards, but there's
plenty of scouts that were ex players.
Do you do you feel that that experience
on the grass for so long gives you an
advantage or kind of changes the way you
see the game a little bit? I think it's
a better lens um overall uh you know
being in the locker room. So it's a
little bit different. I just see in a
little different lens. I'm probably at
times a little bit harder especially
when I'm grading running backs because I
play the position. So that's that's a
little hard for me sometimes just kind
of separated but also know what really
good ones look like. So
>> right you're an expert in the field. So
it's like you better be up to snuff
otherwise I'm not interested in what you
got going on there. But you also
mentioned in that first answer a little
bit about like going into coaching first
then pivoting to scouting. That's also a
common theme that I get from talking to
people like yourself or coaches. they
seem to kind of hit that fork in the
road, then you make a choice. What was
that for you that made you decide like
scouting is the way for me, not
coaching?
>> Well, I I just fell in love with just
the, you know, the why and and just
building a team and and and again, Dick
Heli was one of the best to do it. You
know, you know, he worked with the
Steelers in the 70s and he's built the
steel curtain. So, you know, just being
around him, it just opened my eyes to a
different level and and that I didn't
see in coaching. So, I just was
intrigued by the personnel aspect and
like I said, the why of how you build a
team, how you build a steel curtain, you
know, how do you win those championships
and Super Bowls that that was, you know,
my reason for wanting to go the
personnel route?
>> What does your time look like right now
leading up to the draft? How what are
you going through? How's your
day-to-day, your schedule look like this
time of year?
>> Well, right now, we're kind of
revisiting what we did in the spring,
you know, post combine, um, pro days,
um, you know, kind of revisiting some
information, circling back. That's the
thing you want to do now. security
stuff, background stuff, medical, uh
maybe calling some some sources back at
schools or some of the guys we have
targeted based on the February meetings.
Um so that's what you want to do. Just
circle back, make sure you know all
boxes are checked um before the big day.
Um so there's obviously you don't want
any surprises. So that's kind of what's
been the process. And then on the back
end, just kind of just filling up, you
know, the UDFAs, undrafted free agents,
the back end, the roster. So that's kind
of what we're working on this week. just
kind of make sure all the stuff is is
accounted for for you know so um you
know Sully doesn't have to do any heavy
lifting on on the back end. We've got
all that completed for him.
>> It kind of seems like the answer to this
question is almost what you just talked
about but the inverse of that in the
fall when you're kind of getting going
on the new class. How does that differ
your day-to-day schedule now versus then
where you are cultivating all that stuff
you just talked about where you're kind
of working from a big ball of clay now
you've whittleled it down but how does
it look when you're working with that
initial you know fall scouting off the
summer season?
>> Yeah. Well fall is different. I mean
that's kind of a foundation. Um you know
where we start is Mark Island is our NFS
pre meetings kind of get the the plan
for where we're going. Especially for me
is you know what big schools I have how
I'm building out my schedule, what games
I'm going to. Uh and then obviously
dayto-day you know pretty much every day
I'm in a different school and I kind of
bleed that into the end of the week
where sad I'm at a big game. So, it's a
little bit of a different um schedule
and and and work capacity compared to
now where it's not as stressful because
the travel is different. You know, I'm
sitting here for a week as opposed to
like everywhere I'm somewhere like
Clemson, Georgia, South Carolina, like
every day is somewhere different, you
know, with a game on Saturday. So, no,
not as stressful from a travel
standpoint, but still the workload is is
pretty similar.
>> How many flights you take in a year, do
you think?
>> I'm you know what? Uh I get a lot of
slack for this. I'm more of a drive guy.
I I love to like get in my car. It's
peaceful, man.
>> Yeah, it's peaceful. I'm at my own pace.
You know, I don't have to worry about,
you know, missing a flight or delay. So,
that's that's kind of me. You know,
sometimes they look at me weird because
I I'll drive long distance. For example,
um just last week we're at I was at
Nebraska's proday and I drove back to
Indie. It's 9 hours and I started at
3:00. I got home at 1:00 a.m., you know,
as opposed to flying. But again, I was
at my own pace. I I was okay with it.
You know, the last two hours were hard,
but you know, again, I rather drive than
fly. It's just me.
>> I love the the the behind the scenes
stuff from scouts, man. It's such a cool
job because you guys are doing so much
work behind the scenes that doesn't
always get seen, but you know, talk
about like an area scout versus being a
senior national scout as your job has
evolved over the years. What does that
look like in terms of that, you know,
you you have the scope of the entire
country in a big job, all these schools,
all these players. How do you balance
going deep in terms of knowledge on
players versus having a breath of
knowledge of players across the country?
Like do you do you have to differentiate
like I'm going to focus on this amount
of players or like this quality of
players if that makes sense?
>> Well, um I think it all starts from from
being an area guy because that's the
foundation of building relationships at
different schools and that helps me um
broaden out when I go to bigger schools
or only have one stop, you know, because
as a national scout, you can't circle
back a lot of times because the volume
of schools or the area is so big. So,
you got to trust your relationships. You
got to trust your work ethic, your
ability to get it all done in one day,
which is it's it's pretty hard. And, you
know, there's times my week will be like
Georgia, South Carolina, Clemson. That's
a lot of evaluation. There's a lot of
top end players. That's a lot of guys
that, you know, are we will be
considered for the draft. So, I mean,
it's hard, but I got to rely on my
contacts, um, the area guys,
communicating with them to make sure the
foundation is laid up, like who exactly
am I looking at, you know, because I
can't waste time. I gotta I gotta keep
moving because again the volume of
schools and I got to keep going on to
the next because I don't have the
advantage of circling back like the area
guys. So um it's it's nothing that's you
know again I'm a competitive guy. I like
to challenge. I like to you know be in a
situation where it's hard and it is hard
but it's good. Again, you build
relationships and there's a lot of
coaches that's come through Miami or
just over the course of my career that
I've built relationships where I can
call or circle back or, you know, I'm
out at practice, I can pull it aside and
they may, you know, steer me one way or
another or at least give me another
piece of information. So, it it helps to
know people at the end of the day
because it's a relationship business.
>> Absolutely. It's a little different when
you're going to a a blue blueb blood
program that has maybe 10 five stars
versus a directional school that has one
guy, right?
>> Yes. A lot easier. A lot easier.
>> A lot different. So, something else I
wanted to kind of close here with with
you was you worked as a group leader at
the NFL combine for multiple years in a
row. Just kind of wanted to pick your
brain on what that entails and what you
enjoy about the process and maybe what
you learned from that entire process.
>> First of all, it it's unique and I love
it. Like I'm I'm like I'm driven outside
of Dolphins. That's like that's like my
pet project. Um, you know, each year I'm
excited about the list. I see the list
when men sends me the combine list. Um,
you know, I kind of go through it. First
of all, this the hard part is the
pronunciation of names. So, I go through
this. I'm like, who's these hard names I
got to pronunciate? Cuz I got to get on
the mic and announce these guys. So,
that's that's probably number one. But
number two is, you know, I got four days
to spend with these players. I mean, um,
a lot of these guys, uh, I've seen or
visited at the school, so I got a sense
of who they are and what they are from a
background standpoint. And, and you'd be
shocked. A lot of these guys are
completely different, good and bad. U,
but just four days around somebody, you
know, just lining up. Where's your name
tag? you know, who's on time, who's
late, who communicates, who has a good
personality. I mean, I love it just
being it's another checkpoint just being
around the players and it helps us, you
know, because, you know, we may be on a
clock or come up in meetings like, well,
this guy was in my group, you know, he
was a good player, you know, good
character, he's on time or the opposite,
like, you know, this guy was always
late, you know, had the wrong gear on.
So, it's it's just another checkpoint to
help us uh get to know the player. So, I
mean, I love it. Yeah. And I've been
doing it for multiple years. And and
it's funny because um last night I ran
into T Dot and uh JB and I was like I
said, "It's a small role." And they was
like, they kind of looked at me funny. I
said, "You guys don't realize I was your
group leader at the combine." And they
kind of thought back and they kind of
caught him off. Yeah. Oh yeah. So I mean
it is a small role. Willie Gay, I mean
those are players that I had under me in
in um at the combine, you know, so it
works out.
>> Last one for you here. Uh so has
described the process as collaboration
with boundaries and trust. You've talked
a lot about relationships already. How
would you describe the collaboration
with the rest of the department in this
pre-draft process here in 26?
>> Oh, it's I mean from you guys to
trainers to Drew. I mean I mean it's
it's it's all hands on deck. I mean at
the end of the day I mean you know after
a pro day the first thing I got to do
is, you know, send out an email to to to
Kyle and to for injuries or if anything
pops up from a security standpoint to
Drew and I got a CC Sully and Kyle. So,
I mean, like it's it's a chain of emails
and just communication to make sure
we're all on the same page. Again, no
surprises. So, uh again, it's a team
effort. It's a team effort in all
aspects. I mean, everybody's got to be
on board. I mean, think about it. We're
investing in our future. We all want to
win. We all want a championship. So, we
got to make sure the player we select,
you know, fits the criteria to be a
Miami Dolphin. So, I mean, it's it's a
team effort.
>> Yeah, absolutely. He's on the team that
builds a team for the Miami Dolphins.
Ron Brockington, senior national scout.
Appreciate your time today, man. That
was great. Thank you.
>> Appreciate it.
very special guest, the director of
college scouting for your Miami
Dolphins, Matt Winston. Matt, welcome
back into the show, man.
>> Thanks for having me.
>> I'm excited to have you on here. How's
things been for you? We haven't spoken
since, I believe, last combine.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it's busy. Busy obviously
this time of year.
>> So, during your time here at the Miami
Dolphins, you've had responsibilities
all across the board, pro and college.
Can you kind of pull the curtain back on
that a little bit? Explain the
difference in terms of duties,
responsibilities from college versus a
pro scout.
>> Yeah. Um, it's vastly different. um the
the pro scouting side, you know, you're
you're in the office basically, you
know, 3 365. Um outside of some advanced
work, travel or traveling with the team,
you know, you're you're with the team
dayto-day, you're much more in tune with
what's going on. Uh here in Miami at the
home base, obviously, um you know,
you're in charge of or you're you're
tasked with basically maintaining the
the team evaluations, right? um all the
operations that go into adding players
to the team, you know, with the workouts
going on through through the season, um
monitoring the waiver wires, monitoring
other practice squads, for potential
coaches, and that's from just from a
team standpoint. And then you're also
evaluating the league, right? You're
you're responsible for all the other
free agents, any potential trade
acquisitions. Um and then and then the
pro scouts also handle the advance
evaluations for for the for uh for our
opponents. How many how many total
players would you say that you like
could rip off their like their report on
a given like at a moment's notice?
>> Oh,
>> across the league, college, it seems
like it's in the thousands.
>> Quite a few. I mean, that's the thing
after you've been doing this for so many
years, you know, you just build your
rolodex every year and it just compounds
and compounds and so yeah, you get to
you get to a pretty deep rolodex and
then you you start to forget some some
of them that you wrote a long time ago.
You know,
>> one of the themes we've explored here on
these interviews is is the collaboration
aspect of all which is obviously so key
for you guys, but it's it's such a big
team and you start with this this
massive object, right? The the pool of
players, the pool of, you know, the
workouts that are going to come, the pro
days, the combine, that the tape itself,
and then you work that big ball of of
prospects down to this little, you know,
object that it becomes your your draft
board, right? I imagine a big part of
that is the relationship with with
co-workers and and being, you know, a
director, you have to take on so much
information and try to delegate. How how
does that op how does that operation
work and just how integral are those
relationships for you to do your job?
>> Yeah, I mean it's everything. It's uh
you know, not only the the relationships
within the building, within our staff,
you know, your relationships with
colleges, with coaches, with with staff
administrators that are going to help
you um get information to to really be
able to to do your job and really
network around the league, too. Um
because we we all are kind of especially
on the college side, you know, you end
up seeing a lot of the same faces at all
the same schools and uh you know, having
having networks in in all of those
little branches uh really can kind of
multiply and magnify the the ability for
you to do your job. Um you know, in
terms of just our operation, you know,
we're in constant contact, you know,
every day uh multiple times a day with
with everybody that uh and we're spread
out across the country, right? We have
guys that live all the way from
Pittsburgh to San Diego. So, in terms of
covering the country, you know, through
whether it's via text, phone, whatever.
Um, there's always some kind of
communication going on on a daily basis.
Uh, especially with the climate of
college football with all the transfers,
you have guys, you know, crossing areas
yearly. Um, trying to get make sure that
you're you're tight with your background
and accurate with your background. Um,
you know, we're our scouts are not it's
not only myself, but our scouts are
constantly having to communicate with
each other just to make sure that all
the information is is is tied up and
everything's accurate and and on point
for when we get here to this point in
the process to when we're meeting and
and finalizing the draft board that that
we have the most accurate information
possible.
>> Sure. I don't want to age ourselves here
a little bit, but we've both been doing
this for a long time, you longer than
me. And uh, one of the things that you
have to learn as you get into a job for
decades on end is the advances in
technology. And so I was curious, you
know, getting your start in Houston back
in '06 with all the advances and the way
things have been streamlined, how has
that changed the landscape of a scouter,
a director?
>> Yeah, you can be much more efficient um
with your with your time um you know,
it's the basic, you know, the the
advancement of PFF and all the data that
they that they have available to us and
we use a couple other companies as well.
um that you can just really drill down
into situational football, you know,
alignments, things as simple as just
alignments, like like where you can go
in and watch basically a whole career of
a guy where he's aligned in a certain
spot where in the past that might have
taken you, you know, three days to
figure to to put all the clips together,
you can do it in three minutes now, you
know. So, so there's a the the
efficiency of it. Um and then just from
the the database uh organization
standpoint, information technology is
just uh so so much more advanced than it
used to be in terms of just organizing
the data, making everything uh much more
accessible to everybody and really just
streamline the information flow, you
know, across across multiple levels of
the organization has really just kind of
taken a whole a whole uh new dimension
and added a lot of efficiency to the to
the whole operation. Is it safe to say
that your ability to watch a player rep
count has just increased tenfold over
the time that you've been doing this?
>> Oh, yeah. There's there's no doubt.
There's no doubt. I mean,
>> they used to have to everything used to
be just on beta tapes. So, I mean, now
now everything's obviously obviously
streamed and you don't have to wait for
somebody to finish using the tape. You
can, you know, everything's kind of
accessible.
>> That's amazing, man. Let's close with
this because I want to kind of get back
to the Dolphins here in general. What
excites you most about the 2026 Dolphins
draft? You mentioned 11 picks, you know,
John Eric Sullivan here in in what's
most exciting for you about this cycle?
>> Yeah, it's just opportunity, you know,
to kind of form form the foundation of
of the roster going forward here and,
you know, we've added a lot of free
agents going, you know, in this in the
last month or so. Um, and then just uh,
you know, add a lot of new new young
pieces that hopefully will form the
foundation of a successful team going
forward.
>> Great stuff. New our Dolphins director
of college scouting, Matt Winston.
Appreciate your time today, man. Thank
you so much.
>> Thank you.